Shuvozit Ghose

Summary

An Artificial intelligence (AI) or Machine Learning(ML) engineer / Data Scientist with 5+ years of hands-on experience in machine learning research and development with publications at top conferences (like CVPR, ICCV, ICPR, ICASSP). My expertise encompasses a profound understanding of key machine learning or deep learning concepts, coupled with a comprehensive grasp of data preprocessing, model training, and effective deployment strategies. My practical work has spanned diverse machine-learning techniques, including prompt learning, Large language models (LLMs), graph neural networks, Transformers, graphical models, dimension reduction, clustering, classification, regression techniques, etc.

Education

M.Sc. — Computer Science

Sept 2021 – Oct 2023 University of Manitoba, Canada

Computer Vision Lab

DGPA: 4.20/4.50.

Research Field: Computer Vision, 3D Understanding and Deep Learning

Thesis: CLIP for Point Cloud Understanding Advisors: Prof. Yang Wang and Prof. Yiming Qian

Examiners: Prof. Lorenzo Livi and Prof Carson Kai-Sang Leung

Status: Completed M.Sc. in October 2023.

Google Scholar Citations: 171 (h-index: 7) Google Scholar

Bachelor of Technology — Computer Science and Engineering

Aug 2016 - Aug 2020

DGPA: 8.87/10. Maulana Abul Kalam Azad Univ. of Tech.(IEM), India

Professional Experience -

Graduate Research Assistant | University of Manitoba

Sept 2021 - Oct 2023 | Canada

- Developed 3D Generative AI-based point cloud recognition model utilizing Large language models (LLMs) and image-based geometric deep learning models using Python and Pytorch.
- Developed point cloud classification model performing 3D shape analysis, topology analysis, view geometry analysis, functional mapping, and geometric deep learning.
- Developed Multi-modal deep learning for point cloud classification by connecting Large language models (LLMs) with image models.
- Computed inference using PyTorch on both CPU and GPU running CUDA 11.2 (@Acc > 90%).

Graduate Teaching Assistant | *University of Manitoba*

Sept 2021 – Oct 2023 | Canada

- Collaborated with the instructor and led the lab for undergraduate students for course Comp 2140 (data structure and algorithm using Java).
- Collaborated with the instructor and Graded courses COMP 4360 (machine learning using Python), COMP 2150 (object orientation using Java, C++, and Javascript), COMP 3350 (Software Engineering using Java and Android Studio), and COMP 3490 (Computer Graphics I using processing).

Research Intern | University of Surrey

June 2020 – Mar 2021 | UK

- Developed deep learning model for 2D image and text recognition exploiting neural network architectures, regularization techniques, learning techniques, loss functions, optimization strategies, etc using Python and PyTorch.
- Developed transformer-based 2D text image recognition model for handwriting and scene text recognition using TensorFlow.

Achievements

- 1. Awarded University of Manitoba Graduate Fellowship (UMGF) at the University of Manitoba 2022-2023.
- 2. Awarded International Graduate Student Entrance Scholarship (IGSES) at the University of Manitoba 2021.
- 3. Got NPTEL Elite Certification in Deep Learning for Visual Computing, 2018.

Certification —

Big Data Hadoop by Omega Technologies

• Extracted raw e-commerce data from GitHub and stored it in Hadoop HDFS storage.

- Applied MapReduce for Parallel distributed processing of e-commerce data.
- Utilized Hive for querying and analyzing structured commerce data stored in HDFS.
- Utilized Pig for data processing tasks such as data cleaning, transformation, aggregation, and insights.

Technical Skills

 $Python \mid Pytorch \mid OpenAI \mid Large \ language \ models(LLMs) \mid Natural \ Language \ Processing(NLP) \mid Azure \mid Reinforcement \ Learning(RL) \mid Computational \ geometry \mid Computer \ Vision(CV) \mid GenerativeAI \mid Git \mid AWS \mid Microsoft \ Power \ BI \mid Financial \ Data \mid Docker \mid Kubernetes \mid Software \ Development \ Life \ Cycle \mid CI/CD \mid Tensorflow \mid OpenCV \mid SQL \mid Numpy \mid Panda \mid Java \mid C++\mid C$

Research Background -

(i) Point Cloud Understanding	(ii) Generative Adversarial Network	(iii) Meta-Learning
(iv) Self-supervised Learning	(v) Few-Shot Learning	(vi) Reinforcement Learning
(vii) Prompt Learning & Foundation Model	(viii) Object Detection	(ix) Semi-supervised Learning
(vii) Incremental Learning	(viii) Image Saliency	(ix) Incremental Learning

Notable Projects —

2021 Tokyo Olympic data analytics in Microsoft Azure

- Extracted raw Tokyo Olympic data from GitHub using Azure Data Factory.
- Transformed raw data using Apache Pysparck in Azure Databricks and stored in Azure Data Lake Gen 2.
- Loaded transformed data in Azure Synapse Analytics and Visualized the results using Microsoft Power BI.

Design Personal Website using HTML, CSS, Javascript and AJAX (Demo)

- Designed Personal Website using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and AJAX
- Designed navigation header for the website and hosted on GitHub.
- Integrated Google Analytics for traffic analytics and management.

T 1	•	. •	
Duh	1102	1110	nc

C7	Meta Episodic learning with Dynamic Task Sampling for CLIP-based Point Cloud Classification Shuvozit Ghose, Yang Wang	April 2024
	Conference on Robots and Vision (CRV)(Oral) PDF	
C6	Joint Visual Semantic Reasoning: Multi-Stage Decoder for Text Recognition Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Aneeshan Sain, Amandeep Kumar, Shuvozit Ghose, Pinaki Nath Chowdhury, Yi-Zhe Song IEEE Conference on International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) PDF	Oct 2021
C5	MetaHTR: Towards Writer-Adaptive Handwritten Text Recognition Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Shuvozit Ghose, Amandeep Kumar, Pinaki Nath Chowdhury, Aneeshan Sain, Yi-Zhe Song IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) PDF	June 2021
C4	Modeling Extent-of-Texture Information for Ground Terrain Recognition Shuvozit Ghose, Pinaki Nath Chowdhury, Partha Pratim Roy, Umapada Pal IEEE International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR) PDF	Sept 2020
C3	UDBNET: Unsupervised Document Binarization Network via Adversarial Game Amandeep Kumar*, Shuvozit Ghose*, Pinaki Nath Chowdhury, Partha Pratim Roy, Umapada Pal IEEE International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR) PDF	Sept 2020
C2	Fractional Local Neighborhood Intensity Pattern for Image Retrieval using Genetic Algorithm Shuvozit Ghose, Abhirup Das, Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Partha Pratim Roy Multimedia Tools and Applications PDF	Sept 2020
C1	A Deep One-Shot Network for Query-based Logo Retrieval Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Ankan Kumar Bhunia, Shuvozit Ghose, Abhirup Das, Partha Pratim Roy, Umapada Pal) Pattern Recognition PDF	July 2019

May 2019

User Constrained Thumbnail Generation Using Adaptive Convolutions

CO Perla Sai Raj Kishore, Ayan Kumar Bhunia, **Shuvozit Ghose**, Partha Pratim Roy *International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)*

<u>PDF</u>

References -

Dr. Yang Wang Associate Professor

Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering Concordia University, Canada

Dr. Ruppa Thulasiram

Professor Department of Computer Science University of Manitoba, Canada Phone: +1-514-848-2424 ext 8596 Email: yang.wang@concordia.ca

Phone: +1-204-474-6538

Email: tulsi.thulasiram@umanitoba.ca